Cincinnati, OH 45231 | 513-646-4332 | chrislilley513@gmail.com | Portfolio | Linkedin | github.com/c-lilley-ds |

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data/Business professional seeking a Data Science position which utilizes my skills in data science, analytics, and business strategy to create value for the employer. Three years training in business strategy and marketing, one year of experience with data visualization, two years experience with machine learning, and three years of R programming experience. My portfolio website can be found at https://numbers-are-fun.com

SKILLS

Tableau

R

- Excel
- Html

SOL

CSS

Strategy

- Writing
- Communication

Self Directed Learning

Business Development

• Knowledge of Python at an introductory level

HIGHIGHTED ACCOMPLISHMENTS

PROFESSIONAL DATA SCIENTIST: DATACAMP: Data Science Certification that demonstrates Proficiency in Data Management, Model Development, Exploratory Analysis, Coding for Production Environments, Statistical Experimentation, and Communication and Reporting

EDUCATION EXPERIENCE

Customer Analytics/Post MBA- Xavier University

2019 - 2021

Relevant Coursework: Business Statistics, Statistical Programming, Applied Multivariant Analysis, Data Visualization, Business Analytics for Managers, Consumer Centric Category Management

MBA, Business Intelligence Concentration - Xavier University

2016 - 2018

Relevant Coursework: Data Mining for Managers, Database Management Chase Law School- Northern Kentucky University

2014-2016

BA History Cum Laude- Xavier University

2014

University Scholars Honors Program

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst-Office Assistant

JAN 2023-PRESENT

- Implemented payroll spreadsheet reporting
- Created Covid 19 Tableau dashboard by importing state public records and organizing data in Tableau to mitigate \$13,000 monthly revenue loss, \$8000 in monthly employee retention costs for a staff of four, a Physical Therapist, and 70 patients.
- Obtained \$17120.89 PPP loan in 2020 and \$27254.96 PPP loan in 2021

Analytics Consultant

NOV 2022 - PRESENT

- Created Tableau Dashboard that displays Individual contacts' info on one screen to support business goal of inclusion of individuals with visual impairment
 - Entered Client's Excel Spreadsheet Data into MySQL Database
 - Wrote Queries Using SQL to Clean Data
 - Created Dashboard with text, filters, and highlighter

Digital Assistant

JAN 2018 - JAN 2023

- Implemented record keeping systems and updated directories, spreadsheets, and Quickbooks with accurate data entry to support business planning and development
- Created Covid 19 Tableau dashboard by importing state public records and organizing data in Tableau to mitigate \$13,000 monthly revenue loss, \$8000 in monthly employee retention costs for a staff of four, a Physical Therapist, and 70 patients.
- Obtained \$17120.89 PPP loan in 2020 and \$27254.96 PPP loan in 2021

JUNE 2013 - AUG 2013

Center For Holocaust And Humanity Education, Cincinnati, OH

- Assisted in fundraising, writing copy for press releases
- Researched and wrote notes to be included on plaques next to objects in exhibit Created